(upbeat music)
- Hello English learners,
welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erica.
- And today we're bringing you
the sequel of, I'm sorry, I love you.
- Part two.
- That's right.
- I guess a lot of our
listeners enjoyed the first part.
- Mm-hmm.
- And since it was such
a romantic dialogue.
- Yeah.
- And we're bringing part two.
So it's even more romantic
and I'm sure everyone
is gonna find some great
and useful language in it.
- That's right, we've got language
that we used to talk about dates.
- And date, yeah.
- So useful language for
when you're going on a date.
- That's right.
Well, before we look at this date language,
let's listen to the
dialogue for the first time.
(upbeat music)
- I'm so relieved that
your ankle wasn't broken.
I feel just awful about this whole thing.
I wanna make it up to you.
Let me take you out to
dinner tonight, my treat.
- Well, that sounds great, I'd love to.
Here's my address, pick me up a date.
- Perfect.
- Thank you for such a lovely evening.
My food was amazing and I had a great time.
- Me too.
You look so beautiful tonight.
I wish this night would never end.
There's something that I have to tell you.
- But what is it?
- I woke up today thinking that
this would be just like any other day.
And I was wrong.
Twisted Fate brought us together.
I crashed into your life and you into mine
and this may sound crazy, but
I'm falling in love with you Veronica.
(upbeat music)
- Wow, such a romantic dialogue.
- It really sounds like
they're falling in love.
(laughs)
- Yeah, it's a really romantic
thing that's going on right now,
but there was some
really useful words here.
So why don't we take a
look at language takeaway?
- Language takeaway.
- Today we have three
words for language takeaway.
And the first one is
relieved, relieved, relieved.
So we have some great
examples on how we use relieved
and I'm really sure you can understand
the meaning from the sentences.
- Example one, they were relieved to hear
that the company would
not be making any layoffs.
Example two.
- I'm so relieved to hear your voice.
I was worried something happened to you.
- I guess relieved is like
a happy or relaxed feeling
that you get if you avoid
something bad, right?
- Right, I'm so relieved
that didn't happen.
- Yeah, now for our
second word, pick me up.
Pick me up, pick me up.
- So when you ask someone to
pick you up, you're saying basically--
- Come and get me.
- Okay, so let's give a couple of examples.
My husband was supposed to pick me
up from work yesterday, but he forgot.
- Does that really happen?
- Yes.
(laughs)
- All right, we'll have a talk with him.
Or we could also say,
"Oh, I need to hurry up.
" The taxi will pick
me up at seven.
- Yes, so come and get me.
- Right, yep.
And our final word in today's language
takeaway is ordinary, ordinary, ordinary.
- Ordinary.
- So, ordinary is a normal word.
- Yes, meaning it's normal.
- Nothing uncommon about it.
- Yeah.
- So you can have like an ordinary person.
- An ordinary day.
- Ordinary life.
- Uh-huh.
- Nothing exciting about it.
(laughs)
What else is ordinary?
- Ordinary podcast.
- An ordinary podcast,
which English pod is not.
- It's not.
- Okay. - Yeah.
- So, ordinary.
Okay, great words.
And I guess now we can listen
to our dialogue a second time.
- This time it'll be a little bit slower.
And this will help you to
understand the language more clearly.
(upbeat music)
- I'm so relieved that
your ankle wasn't broken.
I feel just awful about this whole thing.
I want to make it up to you.
Let me take you out to
dinner tonight, my treat.
- That sounds great.
I'd love to.
Here is my address.
Pick me up at eight.
- Perfect.
- Thank you for such a lovely evening.
The food was amazing,
and I had a great time.
Me too.
You look so beautiful tonight.
I wish this night would never end.
There's something I have to tell you.
- What is it?
- I woke up today
thinking this would be just
like any other ordinary
day, but I was wrong.
A twist of fate brought us together.
I crashed into your life and you into mine.
And this may sound crazy, but
I'm falling in love with you, Veronica.
- Okay, so we looked at
some great vocabulary,
and now we can look
at some great phrases.
So let's start with fluency builder.
- Fluency builder.
- Unfluency builder, today
we have three great phrases.
So why don't we just
start with the first one?
- Yeah, the first one we heard at the
beginning of the dialogue, make it up to you.
- Make it up to you.
- Okay, so we have some great
examples on how we use make it up.
So let's listen.
- Example one.
- I'm sorry, I forgot your birthday.
How can I make it up to you?
- Example two.
- I feel terrible for
calling your mother fat.
I wanna make it up to her,
so I got her these flowers.
- Example three.
- John forgot my anniversary again.
He's going to have to make it up to me.
- We can see from the examples that
when you use the phrase make it up to you,
you're kind of saying
you want to balance
something bad you did
with some good action, right?
- Right, so if you call
your mother-in-law fat.
- You better buy her at least
some flowers or a card or something.
- To make it up, right?
- Yeah, yeah.
So the bad action was calling her fat.
And the balancing good
action was the flowers, yeah.
- I don't think flowers
will be enough, though.
- Looks like a doomed marriage.
- Okay, our second phrase, my treat.
- My treat's my treat.
- So we use this phrase when we want
to say, I'll invite you, I'll pay for you.
- I'll pay.
- Right, so I can say, hey,
let's go get some beers.
It's my treat.
- Ooh, thanks, Marco.
- So I'm paying, right?
- Yeah.
- My treat.
And our last phrase for
Fluency Builder, a twist of fate.
- A twist of fate.
- So Erica, what is a twist of fate?
- A twist of fate is an unplanned event
that has a big impact
on your future or your life.
- Okay.
- Marco, can you give us
an example of a twist of fate?
- All right, for example.
Okay, you're supposed to
catch a flight to another country.
All right, but you're late,
so you miss your flight.
- Okay.
- And that flight crashes.
- Wow.
- So that's a twist of fate.
(laughing)
So yeah, it's like fate.
It's like destiny.
- Yeah.
- You weren't supposed
to be on that flight.
- Okay, so a twist of fate.
- A twist of fate.
- Great.
On a happier note, let's listen
to the dialogue a third time.
(upbeat music)
I'm so relieved that
your ankle wasn't broken.
I feel just awful about this whole thing.
I wanna make it up to you.
Let me take you out to
dinner tonight, my treat.
- Oh, that sounds great.
I'd love to.
Here's my address.
Pick me up at eight.
- Perfect.
(suspenseful music)
- Thank you for such a lovely evening.
My food was amazing,
and I had a great time.
- Me too.
You look so beautiful tonight.
I wish this night would never end.
There's something that I have to tell you.
- But what is it?
- I woke up today thinking that
this would be just like any other day.
And I was wrong.
The twist of fate brought us together.
I crashed into your life and you into mine,
and this makes me sound crazy,
but I'm falling in love with you Veronica.
(suspenseful music)
- Okay, so we're back.
Erica, I know you have a story
of a twist of fate in your life.
- Yes, recently, actually, this happened.
I went to this party, and at the party,
there was a contest, like sort of a lottery.
You could buy some
tickets, and win a prize.
And the prize was a week-long vacation.
- Okay.
- So I went with some
friends of mine, and they were
tired, so they left early, and
they gave me their tickets.
And guess what happened?
- What happened?
- We won, we won the week-long vacation.
- Wow.
- Yeah, it was amazing.
So that was a really
lucky twist of fate for me.
- I'm lucky to just a fate, yeah.
That's a good story.
- Yeah, I'm sure it wasn't that good
of a twist of fate for your friends.
- Yeah, but they were very generous,
and let me have the prize anyway.
- All right, well, we
wanna hear your stories
of maybe some type of
twist of fate that you've had.
- Yes.
- Maybe love stories, maybe
tragic stories, any story.
- Mm-hmm.
- So be sure to leave your
questions and comments
and your stories at
our website, englishpod.
com, and where you can also find
us to answer any questions or doubts.
- Yes, that's right.
- So I guess until
then, it's- - Goodbye.
- Bye.
(upbeat music)